<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.zihol.studio</id>
    <title>ZhangZihao</title>
    <updated>2021-04-15T16:07:11.567Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.zihol.studio"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://blog.zihol.studio/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Always be a Student.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://blog.zihol.studio/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://blog.zihol.studio/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, ZhangZihao</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[时光飞逝]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/timeflies/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/timeflies/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-04-15T14:08:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>封面是我的大学毕业典礼的照片，当我偶然发现它时，我感到非常惊讶。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>封面是我的大学毕业典礼的照片，当我偶然发现它时，我感到非常惊讶。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>很久没在我的公众号上写东西了。大家好吗，有没有像那个视频里说得一样，让每一天如约而至？因为好久没分享了，所以今天在这里和大家聊聊，希望大家一切都好。</p>
<p>对我来说，我的意外还是挺多的吧。我的导师几次跟我说要我按照自己的步调，不要一直看别人现在所做的事情，因为每个人都不一样，他们的目标也不一样。</p>
<p>当我回顾从现在到现在的变化时，我真的发现自己变化了很多……变的更多的功利。我总是算自己在研究生中度过的天数以及过了这么多天我有了什么成果。 100天，没有成就，101天，仍然没有，200天，再次。为此真的很累。如果我一直去想我自己，可以从做的或正在做的事情中，能获得什么收益的话，我将不知道自己的生活会怎样。</p>
<p>就像我第一天来到澳大或在家准备来这边的时候，我就在想我要什么时候毕业，然后又害怕做错选择。听起来像一个现实的事实，但是我真的不知道如何处理这些东西，但我又必须去处理他们。可是我也不知道我现在做的这些事情在将来能有什么用，或许我也只有等到了那一天，我才知道，他们可能都是有用的吧。</p>
<p>可是，要知道，身边还有很多同龄人，我也会有意无意的关注到他们，他们中的一些人可能还会发短信给我，例如您为什么如此闲，或者您现在在做什么或者？然后，我真的真的受够了。</p>
<p>不得不说，我在澳大读研究生，有人在我面前说一些漂亮的话，像我的邻居啥的，他们会说例如好学生/儿子之类的，还有的同学可能会说什么有前途或学霸。但是我不知道他们内心深处的真实话语是什么。他们中的一些人可能会在心里想：“看，这个逼浪费了他的时间和金钱。澳大是什么野鸡学校，还这么贵，垃圾。我敢打赌，这个人肯定不会有出息”，之类的，还有更多。</p>
<p>通俗点，就像说，表面上一些人说，哎哟，张子豪在澳门大学真厉害啊，背地里也不知道这些人是怎么想的，他们认为的成功应该就是钱和权吧。</p>
<p>因此，真的很难对付它们。所以，我也知道只用去过好自己的生活然后找到自己的节奏。人有千面，你知我几分。我们都需要专注于自己。我只想与真正关心或支持我的人分享一些想法，非常感谢亲爱的您。</p>
<p>有时我会选择接受所有这些，包括像有些人就是可能永远比我更好，就像我真的需要重新思考我的生活并接受这种平凡。有时我知道我必须信仰一些东西让我自己不被打到而我做到了。</p>
<p>我很高兴我还有很多话要说。</p>
<p>史蒂夫·乔布斯（Steve Jobs）说：“有勇气跟随自己的内心和直觉。他们以某种方式知道自己真正想要成为什么。“去找到自己的热爱，如果还么找到就继续找，不要妥协。”</p>
<p>如果你看到这里这里，您可以在下面评论“努力！奋斗！”，让我们现在开始做。 慢慢来，最终所有点都将连接起来。</p>
<p>非常感谢，也真的感谢那些比我更好或更糟的人，我知道你们永远不会看轻我而且一直站在这里。 我爱你们。</p>
<p>结束。</p>
<p>非常感谢，也真的感谢那些比我更好或更糟的人，谢谢你们从不看轻我而且一直站在这里。我爱你们。</p>
<p>再见。<br>
<img src="https://blog.zihol.studio/post-images/1618496981551.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten Questions]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/ten-questions/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/ten-questions/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-03-03T08:11:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, Dear March, Good Luck to Me.</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, Dear March, Good Luck to Me.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p><em>The questions in the email are listed below. If you feel anxiety or lack of sense of security, then you can answer them after thinking twice. From Liu's book, &quot;I am I&quot;, which is my terrible translation.</em></p>
<p><strong>Q1. Do you study or work in a city away from home and why? Do you still remember the feelings or minds you came here the first time?</strong><br>
Yes, I am in Macao to pursue my master's degree, because I wanna know where is my ceiling and how high it is. Of course, I remember it. I felt so easy for all of the new things and so so.</p>
<p><strong>Q2. How much money can release your stress in your opinion? and if you get a lot of money, what will you do with this money?</strong><br>
How about 1 million, and if I have a lot of money, I will use it to increase the real estate price, lol.</p>
<p>Now I am poor for anything, how dare I can say I wanna 1 million deposit. No house, no car, but if I have my own family in the future, I will not be so stressed to deposit. Both she and I are normal people and we can earn money step by step. Considering the accident in our life, I think 500k may be suitable. It's so funny here, I think 500k is a small number but I can't get any of them. So weak.</p>
<p>In fact, my personality is positive, I am optimistic about everything and I am not willing to be guided by money. However, money is really important in our daily or not daily life, but here I won't emphasize its significance for us. Because there are so many people and things reminding us of that.</p>
<p>If I face this question after serval years and at that time I have an amount of money. Opening a coffee shop, a barbershop, or other shops like this which can play my favorite music every second may be one of my choices. Also, I can travel around the world with this money. And I will experience it before, then take my families and friends to travel again with my guideline. Sometimes, I am wondering that buying a big house near The West Lake sounds so great......</p>
<p><strong>Q3. The darkest period in your life.</strong><br>
JK, My sky seems all turn grey when I enter 2020.</p>
<p>It sounds not very well now, but I deeply feel and experience it now. More specifically, I can cut off the days I stay at home, which means the day in Macao, so sad about this and hope it's not true. When I recap my childhood, although there is some blur. I enjoyed the pressure only from the homework in my primary school. I collected my middle school time into the wonderful album. At that time, I won a good grade with a good face and singing songs at our New year's Eve Party, really awesome. High school, happiness with light pain in my second semester of the third year. My performance in score decreased month by month from top 100 to top 150 and... Until the College Entrance Exam, top 300 or 400. Then, during my undergraduate, I felt the freedom given by my parents, myself. I can do what I wanna do, singing contests, debate competitions, enjoying a concert... I even don't afraid of the absence of class. When I encountered some difficulties, my classmates always can help me to figure them out. How about the postgraduate now, before I intend to pursue my master's degree, I wanna do some research on computer graphics, but there is no professor doing such kind of topic in UM, and I did lots of non-meaningful things.</p>
<p>In a word, it seems that I haven't suffered any darkest time in my life, because I still so naive to all of the things and the cruel society I haven't met it.</p>
<p><strong>Q4. The last time you cried, for what?</strong><br>
Away from my dear grandpa forever.</p>
<p>I am not sure about it. I am a crying guy, but I think I haven't cried after that.</p>
<p><strong>Q5. Three years later, what will you do as far as your concerned?</strong><br>
A worker, PM, Programmer,</p>
<p>Who can know what we will do after three years like now I am a student studying abroad and I haven't thought about it before. But if I do the wish, I hope I am pursuing my Ph.D. still study abroad.</p>
<p><strong>Q6. How did you meet your best friend?</strong><br>
How to define the best friend? I made my friends because we have the same goal, or we have the same topic to chat with, or he can understand my and my shortcomings, listening to me and giving advice.</p>
<p>The best friend, It's really an embarrassing question for me. I always being told or thinking I am a person without friends. Sometimes if I view A as my best friend, but the BFF of A is B, not me. Also, no best, just friends, I regard A as my friend, but A may think that he can't use friend the word to recognize each other. Therefore, I will protect myself very well.</p>
<p>Actually, now most of them we met in school, and in fact, I may hate some of them when we were in school. But after a long time, I can feel they are still willing to accompany me and caring about my feelings. I also know I have occupied a little space of their heart. Sometimes, one of us two may stop the pace, or change to other roads, but every time we need each other, we always can find him still in the place we meet.</p>
<p>If I have to talk about more, I have to say I'm not an active man, I have to worry about lots of things. If I become active with you, which means I wanna make friends with you, and if you look down on it then I will throw it. What hell I am talking about.</p>
<p><strong>Q7. Are there any changes in your life? if no changes, why? and if changes, what preparations you have done or you're doing?</strong><br>
Certainly, but I haven't done any preparations now.</p>
<p>After all, I am a young man now, I am also willing to accept all the changes in my life however good or bad. If I have to answer it, I will say the only preparation I have done is throwing my self-abased and negative away from my life and equipping myself with courage that can face all the challenges. I haven't prepared it before, which is my mantra. I lost the opportunities, made things complicated due to it, but it is just our life, our living life. If the preparations about the positive changes, I just keep a healthy body to continue.</p>
<p><strong>Q8. Did you still remember your dream in your study time? how about it? Are there any friends you are familiar with achieving their dreams?</strong><br>
Of course, Lanzhou University, Central South University, and Zhejiang University all my dream universities, but I failed all. My friends? Have to say, I have no idea about it, maybe some. It has been a long day I haven't talked about dreams with someone. Many people always said earning money and being rich and let the dream kiss their ass. But there is also a situation that they don't wanna talk about their dreams with me, It is such a big sad thing.</p>
<p>And other dreams like traveling abroad in my undergraduate, I was thinking I can unlock some domestic and foreign cities, but I haven't gone any places out of China. I always believe that our eyes see more and our heart tolerates more.</p>
<p><strong>Q9. What's the biggest lonely of us in your views?</strong><br>
I think the most lonely is that when someone has a big victory or a terrible loss and the only person he wants to run to tell isn't there, and he can't find more people to share.</p>
<p><strong>QX. What's your best advantage?</strong><br>
My shinest advantage, this question really tough.<br>
I wanna say I am a sincere person, I am a human with a warm temperatures.<br>
What hell it is?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Chinese New Year of Ox]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/happycny/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/happycny/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-02-18T08:54:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If I always stop here to think about those things again and again, how can I celebrate my New Year of Ox and continue to pursue your dream and keep the heart.</em></p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If I always stop here to think about those things again and again, how can I celebrate my New Year of Ox and continue to pursue your dream and keep the heart.</em></p>
<!-- more -->
<br/>
<p align="center">
<iframe width="560" height="315"  src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QVmTeSEzvmE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
<br/>
<p>此刻我正在距离家乡七百公里外的城市写下新年的祝福，这是我第一次自己一个人迎接新春，身边没有家人朋友的陪伴，也听不到爆竹的声音，就这样对着电脑，看着手机，有人发消息来我就回复，听到好听的歌曲就单曲循环一会儿，刷到有意思的新闻就往下去深挖，淘宝上看到想买的东西就加入购物车，偶尔也去微博偷窥别人的生活，普通又正常。心里面还在想，<strong>我拥有的还是侥幸，我失去的还是人生</strong>。</p>
<p>以往过年的时候，早上起来我给父母亲拜年，他们都会跟我说步步高升，遥看这一年的点点滴滴，问自己有一步一步地在高升吗？<br>
<em>拿到了新的身份，却还没有做出在这个身份上的成绩</em>；<br>
<em>学到了一些新的知识，却要面对，如何在更广阔的的世界里遨游</em>；<br>
<em>经过了岁月的洗礼，得到了年龄的增长，却还是伴随着对于人生，不确定的迷茫</em>；<br>
<em>适应了新的环境，却还是不会社交，假装自信，其实自卑平庸，地走在要把他乡作故乡的街头</em>；<br>
<em>习惯了“一个人真好”的状态，却还是，在夜晚独自从图书馆走出来的时候，渴望着被人惦记，有人诉说</em>；</p>
<p>我的身边仍然是这些一个个的“<strong>却</strong>”包围着，<br>
我还是会假装很自信地，昂首提胸走在异乡；<br>
我也还是一样自卑又平庸，放手那些宿命的机会；<br>
我还是一样不爱社交，喜欢和不喜欢都永远分明；<br>
我还是会迷茫，在面对无数个不确定的选择的时候；<br>
此刻的我也没有什么新的成绩；<br>
我还是对很多事情很无知，没有办法在这个广阔的计算领域自由的翱翔；<br>
我还是很渴望被人知道，被人惦记，被人需要；</p>
<p>此刻的我慢慢开始去和这些新的东西和解，<br>
我不再害怕以后没有人爱；<br>
也不再害怕那一次次让我崩溃的压力；<br>
那些失败，那些嘲笑，那些期待，那些陪伴，<br>
那些傲慢与偏见，那些情谊和支持，还有那个真正的我，<br>
我也不再害怕，安心地，就这样让他们全部暴露在阳光之下。</p>
<p>我一边迎接和拥抱这些我曾经把它们当作困扰的东西，去表露更真实的自己；<br>
一边努力去解决，在一次次的尝试中算出问题的满分答案。</p>
<p>我一边听信和敬畏着“都是命”的表述，更正确地处理当下的得与失；<br>
一边拼尽全力去做好正在进行的每一件事，用更良性的从容去接受每一次遗憾。</p>
<p>今年是牛年，去年，我们的鼠年过得并不顺利，<br>
疫情让我们生活，的每一次出发都变得沉重，<br>
戴上口罩，出示健康码，核酸检测，居家健康监测，集中隔离，<br>
我们的每一步都必须先问自己更多的问题，去保证我们的出行顺利。</p>
<p>这些也让我想到，我们的人生，我们的进步，是不是同样的需要沉重，<br>
如果不够沉重，我们又怎么可以顺利地到达，<br>
每一次的沉重，都是在为最后完美结果的保障。</p>
<p>我想了很久，除了牛气冲天、牛转乾坤这样的烂掉牙的词语，我还可以说什么，<br>
我说，我不在纠结于，那些问题，而是勇敢地，直面和接受，自己的人生；<br>
我说我们需要沉重来证明我们所走的每一步都是为了进步，越沉重，往往越顺利；<br>
我说了好多好多。我想你们也一样吧，<br>
在和自己对话的时候，也曾告诉自己不断向前看，告诉自己要做一个快乐的打工人。<br>
<b>所以呢，祝愿大家新的一年新的每一天，都是自己曾经对自己说过的，应该是，这样那样，的每一天。</b>🤞<br>
<img src="https://blog.zihol.studio/post-images/1613639396874.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking and Thinking]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/thinking-and-thinking/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/thinking-and-thinking/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-22T06:41:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Somrtimes I always stuck in a mood, how to say, just a deep deep depression, I don't know how to figure out the confusion and I think there is also a problem that scientist can't.</em></p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Somrtimes I always stuck in a mood, how to say, just a deep deep depression, I don't know how to figure out the confusion and I think there is also a problem that scientist can't.</em></p>
<!-- more -->
<p>就像大家会说死线是第一生产力，对我来说，我也会拖到死线去完成，但并不是死线的压力让我可以完成我的工作，我在一开始打算把它放到死线再完成的时候我就知道我自己有能力可以完成它。有的时候我也会高估自己，而这个时候我必须面对真正的死线压力，我就会变得焦虑，它也并不能转换成动力，而我也只能在消极和自我否定之中完成一份不完美的作业，拖延不是什么好的习惯。</p>
<p>不喜欢压力，而又要面临压力，这就是情绪的爆发所在。</p>
<p>回想这些年推动我向前的是什么，是我的乐意和家人朋友的支持，高中的时候想进入好大学，可是没有进入好大学（现在不是，希望以后是吧），于是大学的时候想和身边的人不一样，想追综艺就追，想看电影就去，想逛街就走，想学习就肝，奖学金有就有没有就没有……<br>
我根本不想去在乎身边的人，我会一直告诉自己，我不是当下这个圈子里的人，他们和我不是一类人，这样的自大和狂妄也让我吃了很多亏，失去了很多人和机会。</p>
<p>而到了现在，我想，想不明白，路越来越宽敞，好像前面的每个方向都有光，也都有荆棘……<br>
而就是这样的想不明白，让我开始观察在意那些同辈压力，<br>
我在想我比不上他那么会社交，我比不上他那么会学习，我比不上他那么有钱，我比不上他有那么多好朋友，我比不上他那么坚定自己的目标，我比不上他已经做了那么多工作，我比不上他已经有了可以守护一生的人，我比不上……<br>
或许有的同学可以把这些都暗自转化成为自己前进的动力，大家也会告诉我那就努力啊，努力去做到这些，但是我没有办法，这些话会像蚊子一样在我的两个耳朵旁边吵吵吵吵个不停，最后被它打败，放声大喊，我需要爱，我需要陪伴，我需要别人告诉我，会一直在我身边，不会因为我比不上，就让我一个人，<br>
而我也就这样慢慢失掉了我应有的理性。</p>
<p>我很感谢那些鼓励我的朋友们，还有你们分享的走出困境的办法。大家也会说先把手头上的事情做好，不要想那么多，可是在手头上没有事情的时候要去自己选择做什么事情，那又是一个困境。<br>
我明白遇到问题不能逃避，只有去讨论它，说出你的决定，你的担心，才有机会看到前方是哪一方，然后，现在的我，也已经看到了那个要向前的方向。</p>
<p>我也总是觉得让别人理解自己的感受是一件很难的事情，很多同学反正可能会觉得是在无病呻吟，&quot;明明过着很好的生活，干嘛还要这么消极，比你糟糕的人一大把，老铁真没必要这么装&quot;，有些时候听到还是会觉得失望，想想也就算了，一堵墙在那里，我们都不愿意翻过去对面看看，</p>
<p>我也希望大家永远不要体会我的这种感受，而当你不幸也这样感受，还一定记得，不想去努力让自己变得振作起来也没关系，因为好运就在你身边，未来会好好地来。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary01]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/diary01/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/diary01/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-06T23:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I wrote my diary here to express my minds and when I start to write this, which means I have a long time without any friend to share my bad or good feelings, so here, pleaze let me dance.</em></p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I wrote my diary here to express my minds and when I start to write this, which means I have a long time without any friend to share my bad or good feelings, so here, pleaze let me dance.</em></p>
<!-- more -->
<p>我看到了我本科院QQ号在发运动会的消息，思绪一下子就拉回去2016年，我刚来到学校，9月底10月初的时候开始每天晚上要去田径场训练八字跳。对，我是一个很没有运动细胞的人，但是我的内心还是喜欢运动的。希望大家都要热爱运动经常运动才好。那时候好像必须每个人都要报一项，我就选了个站在那里摇绳的人，听着简单，发现实际操作起来还是压力很大的，跳绳的同学被绊倒了，也会有意无意自己觉得是没有摇好。</p>
<p>我翻了那个QQ号的动态，我看到他发了很多喜报 ，什么什么项目又获得了前八名。我在想能不能翻到2016年看看有没有那时候的记录，然后那个QQ号在2015年11月的时候停止了运营，直到2017年10月又才重新回来。</p>
<p>回忆又来到2017年，那时候已经在学生会当了部长，可以训练那些大一的新生们，训练也谈不上，就是监督一下，最后好像是进了前八名学院会给我们发钱。那一年的项目叫做火车跑，然后好多都是我们部门的同学在那，那段时间还挺开心的，反正很自由。</p>
<p>大二在青志协那一年，好像都还挺开心的，觉得很有存在感，所以开心。然后还看了那时候自己的图片在一些活动的合照里面，觉得那时候自己的穿着一言难尽。不过样子感觉就总是现在这个样子也没有变。然后看到2015年动态里面的同学，再看到2020年的同学，发现图片不止是清晰度的差别，照片里面每个人散发的气质也因为年代的不同而有了一点点变化，可能更光鲜亮丽，所以更自信，也更大胆了一点。</p>
<p>今年有表弟表妹高考结束进入大学，有一次和表妹讲了很多东西，然后她也只是回我说我知道的，竟然觉得有一点失望在，不知道为什么。表弟也是读的计算机，但是有很多话又不知道该怎么说，他来问我本科有没有加社团协会什么的，我也只是简单的说了一些，专业上我也只是说要多去敲代码，上上网课，自学很重要。问自己还有什么建议是可以给到他们的吗，好像有又好像没有，但是就是没有说了，然后看着手机屏幕暗掉，聊天结束在了谢谢哥。</p>
<p>我也没有年长多少，但是这样的感受就让我想起来，其实我每一次有了什么问题，什么决定，我的父母，是不是其实内心也会有很多想说又不知道怎么说的话，然后最后都是沉默了，觉得这是我自己的路，就让我自己去走，不用听太多的声音，去相信自己的选择。</p>
<p>我又打开了朋友圈，看到好多人都发着橘子相关的内容，突然也很想吃橘子，有的人发了都是黄色的满屏幕的橘子，表姐夫发了在橘子树下的照片，老同学发了一篮子的橘子。</p>
<p>来到这边之后，其实也有一直在吃水果，买的最多的应该就是橙子了，第二就是柚子，这边的柚子不知道为什么，我感觉应该是很便宜了，一般就是12或者13澳门币一个，最近人民币的汇率好像还可以，6月份那会儿都是89块人民币等于一百块澳门币，现在一百块澳门币只要84块。这边很多都是按个卖，苹果，桃子，橙子都是按个数在卖，然后柚子便宜的时候还有九块九澳门币一个，红肉的、普通的价钱也一样。</p>
<p>然后别的水果就好多都是进口，就没有来自内地的，像香蕉就没有，橙子好像有，但是价钱和非洲进口差不多，然后还有李子，葡萄什么之类的也都是只有进口的。看到国外比来自国内的便宜的，就是摆在货架上写着产地美国的鸡蛋要比产地中国的鸡蛋便宜一些。</p>
<p>最近有什么开心的事情，就是昨天是22号嘛，然后看到网易云的每日推荐变成了生日蛋糕的样子，虽然之前也知道，但是这次把每日推荐收藏了，想着以后每一年都收藏，还挺有意义的。然后打卡一些app还都有提醒，虽然不意外，但是还挺意思的，特别是打开中国银行app的时候，满屏幕都变成了金黄色，一股酒店风格袭来。还有星巴克给了我一张任意中杯饮料免单的券，还挺不错的。下个月22号是这个公众号的第四年了，到时候呢会有一个送你们明信片的活动，2020也没几天了是吧。</p>
<p>写着写着，想到我应该要说点有意义的东西，哎，什么又是有意义的呢……</p>
<hr>
<p>那上面的内容就是昨天23号的时候在手机上，坐在电脑前拼凑起来的内容啦。今天去超市买了橘子，我不知道有多少，反正一袋13澳门币。晚上吃酸辣米线的时候在看说唱新世代，觉得其实我们人，真的选择可以有好多，但是可以唯一代表你的又好少。这时候又想到了jj新专辑的Drifter里面的一句歌词，想要闪烁就对自己更严格，嗯，就是这样唱的。</p>
<p>就像见面会聊天气，澳门这边的天气似乎还不错这段时间，是刚好穿短袖不会出汗的时候，可以穿着短袖短裤，然后在套个外套，套个衬衫啥的，刚好。</p>
<p>我的微信消息界面会置顶我收藏里面的一个笔记，里面就是每次我想到什么就会往里面写，然后写下当时的时间，我刚刚打开去看发现是15号的时候写的“立大志 上大舞台 入主流 干大事业”，你们有印象吗？我一读到就知道是在讲清华选调生的视频里面说的清华的教育是这种家国情怀的教育。</p>
<p>说到教育，应该有一些日子了吧，我看到了也是说之前讲学术人生的一篇文章，它里面也是说很多国内的学生在做科研的时候都是带着功利的心态，“我这个方向发论文容不容易”，“我要选什么课题会好做一点”。巧的是，前些天，我和一位老师聊天，我说我想继续在学术方面有更多的训练，然后我说我想两年就毕业，然后他说，你想两年就毕业，你也太功利了，这样是做不成科研的，你们从内地来的学生就是这点不好，反正后面发生了很多，那位老师也很好，让我迷茫又彷徨了好一阵子，有机会去撕开一些（这里我本来想用 思考 的，没想到输入法直接就 撕开 发现撕开好像也还不错，用在这里）我自己的，存在的问题。</p>
<p>那现在可以说的就是，我们应该要珍惜自己的学习机会，毕竟一方面这的确从每个人来说，到自己身上可能都是来自不易的，你来到现在的位置，所以要珍惜自己的学习机会。至于会被教育成怎样的人，还是取决于自己想要什么，就会去选择什么啦！说那种家国情怀的教育也好，个人意志的追求也好，其实环境，它在影响我们做选择的能力上，是没有我们自己的价值观那么强大的。可是呢，价值观的形成也和我们的环境有着很大的联系，这。。。我们还可以做梦，不是，在自己的世界里，可能。</p>
<p>Emmm，我不知道你们会不会有这样的情况，就是有个人很能影响到你的生活，你可能讨厌他，或者喜欢他，反正她就是在那里，不说一句话，从你面前走过去，你就会感觉，你被影响到了。或许是积极的影响，也许是消极的影响。</p>
<p>现在想写一首诗，即兴的，现代诗，啊哈哈哈哈，开始了</p>
<p>下午四点半</p>
<p>阳光正好全部晒在这条街上</p>
<p>街道两旁种满了树</p>
<p>还有和树一样高的房子</p>
<p>我们挥了挥手</p>
<p>你朝着阳光在的那边走去了</p>
<p>我没有跟着你</p>
<p>但我也没有背对阳光</p>
<p>阳光就在我的侧脸</p>
<p>跟着我 回到了我的家</p>
<p>......</p>
<p>什么鬼嘛</p>
<p>好的，公众号的更新就是这样猝不及防还特别神奇，结束也是很突然。</p>
<p>突然发现没有插图，我其实最近有拍一些图片，但是微信，为什么登陆了Windows就会退出iPad，然后没有想到什么好的、快的传输图片的方法之前，就不想弄了，除非要剪视频，可能苹果在这方面的生态会方便一点。还有很多事情其实也没说，但是呢，也不代表我就忘了，啊哈哈哈哈，老史铁生了，我与地坛，对，其实我什么都记得，大家也要都记得。</p>
<p>为了大家，我还是搞了一张图片过来。</p>
<p>我去洗澡了，各位晚安。</p>
<p>一定要听歌，好吧！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.zihol.studio/post/hello-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.zihol.studio/post/hello-2021/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-06T22:37:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>2020 is a bad year, we all suffered a lot. I have to graduate from my undergraduate school and seprate my classmates my friends from my life, I miss them, I miss my 20, however, they are all gone.</em></p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>2020 is a bad year, we all suffered a lot. I have to graduate from my undergraduate school and seprate my classmates my friends from my life, I miss them, I miss my 20, however, they are all gone.</em></p>
<!-- more -->
<!-- more -->
<p>今年我毕业了，回到学校的时间也就只有三天，和同学一起去了毕业典礼，遗憾的是都没有拍照。刚从学校回到家的那几天，我的心情一直很失落，害怕我以后再也没有机会和他们聊天说话。这种情感，是我高中的时候不曾有的，尽管我要喜欢我的高中远远胜过我的任何一个求学阶段。可能是高中大家都在一个地方，即使开始了不同的生活，但是过年，大家还是会再回来。这样的失落情绪也没有持续很长，我很快从中调整过来了，因为还有很多事情等着我去做。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>细数我在东华理工求学的这四年，整个的状态是很舒服的一个状态，我所有的学习，所有的看书，都是因为我想去看，我想要去学，每次的考试，我想要拿到一个高分，我就会在期末前好好冲刺补课一下；如果觉得无所谓，我也不会强迫自己一定要达到什么。我的室友说我经常玩，我也很高兴，在这四年，我做了很多让自己开心的事情。有开心也会有遗憾，遗憾的就是没有抓住时间更好的去强化自己的专业技能。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>大三下学期的时候我在准备考研了，我很想考上，但是就是没有考到。这也让我知道我其实没有那么厉害，厉害到可以掌控自己的一切，我需要加强的，还有很多很多。<br>
考研结束后，公布成绩前的那段时间，我其实已经知道我没有什么希望了。那时候我开始找了一些岗位，笔试通过，在面试的时候，面试官问我我选择这个工作的原因已经我的就业规划等等，我想了很久，我都想不出来，我脑子里只想着我想要读研究生，我希望有自己的研究成果。这样消极就业的态度一直持续着，我一边投着简历，一边消极地准备，一边参加着笔试，一边拒绝着面试，一边在面试的时候语无伦次，循环着，我也知道我在大学三年所学的知识完全不足以让我找到一份好的工作。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>后面，成绩公布，我没有考上。我跟我的导师说了，他问我要不要考虑去港澳那边的学校，他推荐了一个在澳大读电子商贸的学姐联系方式给我，我后面自己提交了所有的申请材料，因为疫情，我的成绩单一直弄不下来，知道申请的最后一天，我才把我的成绩单提交上去。学姐建议我去电商，说计算机科学的招生要求会更严格，当时心里就想，就计算机科学吧，没有就没有了。提交申请之后我也再没有去理这件事。直到四月中旬，澳大把我放在了waiting list里面，候补。我一边忙着我的毕业论文，毕业答辩，一边看着2021考研的一些数学书，学着自己喜欢捣鼓的一些视频剪辑等等。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>五月份的时候，很多同学都收到了复试通知，拿到了录取资格。我也是消极的来到了调剂系统里面，随便填了几个调剂申请，填了杭电，北方工业大学，云南大学等等，最后只有杭电给我发了复试通知。面试就在两天后，因为选择的是网络空间安全系，我心里在想，我两天要怎么看完，其中一天还是答辩日。没有准备，我就放弃了。另外一个调剂到杭电的同学成功地去向了杭电。当时也很开心。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>五月底六月初的时候，澳大终于发来了offer，我没想到竟然被录取了。就这样，我来到了澳大。<br>
来到澳大之后，其实一直没有找到，没有进入研究的那种状态，只是上着课，做着作业，看着论文，做着pre.......</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>就这样，结束了2020，我的2020好像没有一件值得拿出来说的事情，我丢弃了以前爱看书的好习惯，疫情期间坚持了三个月的跑步也已经断了不知道几个月了，代码也没有，只是完成了必须要完成的，</p>
<!-- more -->
<p><strong>如果2020我是一个loser的话，2021我希望我可以抓住时间，不断进化！</strong></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>